

# Carlos Crisóstomo Vals























Madrid, Spain



linkedin.com/in/ccvals



github.com/Kr0n0



# **EDUCATION**

**MSc in Artificial Intelligence** UNIR, La Rioja 2018-2020 (All but dissertation)

> **MSc in Cybersecurity** UNIR, La Rioja 2016-2018 (Not finished)

**Computer Engineering Degree** UPSAM, Madrid 2014-2016

MPM (Master of Project Management) PMP - PMBOKv5 CAS Training, Madrid 2014

**Technical Engineering in Computer** Systems UPSAM, Madrid

2000-2012

## **LANGUAGES**

**English** Fluent French Fluent Spanish

Mother tongue

# **ABOUT ME**

I am an Engineer with more than 25 year-experience in Open Source and GNU/Linux systems.

During my professional career I have been in continuous learning with different higher education programs, courses, and specialization trainings.

Alongside several heterogeneous technical fields going from cybersecurity to artificial intelligence through embedded systems, my professional career has evolved into high technical management and product development.

As project manager and team lead, I oversaw remote teams in several technical fields. Working as a freelancer has helped me to fulfill key skills in management such as assuming by myself big responsibilities in international projects.

I like to work with innovative technology groups. This is why I am looking for new challenges in technical management, leading global work teams in an ambitious international project.

## **EXPERIENCE**

2020 - Present

The Bridge - Digital Talent Accelerator

Lead Cybersecurity Instructor #INFOSEC #TEACHING

2019 - Present Xift

Owner | AI / Infosec / Embedded Systems Consultant #ENTREPRENEUR #AI #INFOSEC #MANAGEMENT #EMBEDDED #CONSULTANCY

2019 - 2020 **Crystal Robotics** 

CTO / AI Robotics Engineer

#AI #EMBEDDED #MANAGEMENT #ROBOTICS #STARTUP

2015 - 2019 Freelance

Embedded Operating Systems Expert

#ENTREPRENEUR #CONSULTANCY #MANAGEMENT #EMBEDDED #INFOSEC

2018 **MIOTI - Madrid Internet of Things Institute** 

Associate Professor

#INFOSEC #TEACHING

2015-2017 **EthelHub** 

CEO / Founder

#ENTREPRENEUR #INFOSEC #MANAGEMENT #EMBEDDED #STARTUP

## SKILLS

Team Management

Project Management (PMP/SCRUM)

**Product Development** 

Machine Learning

Pentesting / Ethical Hacking

Reverse Engineering

Linux Kernel and Embedded OS

Edge AI (Embedded AI)

## **COURSES**

#### Management

SCRUM Master Training and Certification (Xsfera)

Fundamentals of Marketing (University of Pennsylvania, Coursera)

Lean Startup and Design Thinking (Google Activate)

#### **Artificial Intelligence**

Machine Learning with TensorFlow on Google Cloud Platform Specialization (Google Cloud, Coursera)

Machine Learning (Stanford University, Coursera)

## Cybersecurity

Cyberwar - Advanced Offensive Cyber Operations (StrategicSec)

Mobile iOS/Android Forensics (Securizame)

Practical Ethical Hacking (OSCP) Training (Securizame)

## **Embedded Systems**

Intro to Zynq Architecture with Vivado HDL (Xilinx)

Embedded Linux OS design under ARM9 platform (Atmel)

Real-time OS design (ULMA Embedded)

Booting-time speed up and optimization under GNU/Linux Embedded Systems (Montavista)

## DevOps

Official Docker Training (Docker)

## EXPERIENCE

2012-2015 Arteche Smart Grid

Operating Systems D&D Dept. Manager / Project Manager #EMBEDDED #MANAGEMENT #INFOSEC

2011-2012 Sistemas Avanzados de Control

Head of Operating Systems D&D / Project Manager #EMBEDDED #MANAGEMENT

2008-2011 Sistemas Avanzados de Control

IT Systems Technical Manager / Systems Analyst #SYSADMIN #MANAGEMENT

2010 CICE

Training Collaborator
#TEACHING #SYSADMIN

2006-2009 TNS Global

Technological Expert Panelist Collaborator #CONSULTANCY

2005-2008 Unisys Consulting

Systems Analyst #SYSADMIN

2005-2008 Telefónica Group
Systems Analyst (TData/TdE/TME)

#SYSADMIN #INFOSEC

2005 Unisys Consulting

Systems Specialist #SYSADMIN

2004 Unisys Consulting

Systems Internship / Grant Holder #SYSADMIN

2000 Join Free Business

Junior Developer

## PRESENT AND PAST AFFILIATIONS

Project Manager Institute (PMI) – Madrid, Spain Chapter

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) – Spain Section

Linux Foundation (LF)

Free Software Foundation (FSF)

EuropeanScrum.org

OWASP Foundation - Madrid, Spain Chapter

Asociación Española de Inteligencia Artificial (AEPIA)

European Al Alliance (European Commision)

Hackmadrid %27